Once upon a time, there was a maiden.
The maiden wore tattered clothes and was called Cinderella.
But with the help of some magic, she became a beautiful princess and got to dance with the prince.
Then, at the stroke of midnight, the maiden ran away, leaving a glass slipper, and she returned to being Cinderella once again.
The prince went to great lengths to find this maiden, which he did, and took her as his wife.
Yet, a thorny question arises.
Did the prince really fall in love with the maiden?
That's right, I am a crow.
And I alone am the true prima donna, Princess Cray-hee.
I'll take what I desire by force if need be.
Princess Tutu, will you not cease this restoring of his heart then?
No, because that is the Prince's wish.
Do you intend to shatter his heart again?
If I do...
I won't allow you to.
You'll kill me then?
What?
Could you kill?
That's not...
Stop!
And when the raven stands before you, strike!
You can't guard Mewtwo with just heart shards!
But Cray-hee, she was suffering.
Then that was your chance!
I would've finished her, and if it came down to it, I could even kill you too.
Tutu, run!
Why must you hinder me from regaining my heart, Fakir?
Hinder?
My heart.
I want to get my heart back.
No matter what fate might then await me.
I just...
Fakir...
You're trembling.
Why?
What is that?
When in the world did I go back to being a duck?
I know!
What?
Why?!
Why did I turn back into a girl?
Shhhhhh!
The pendant...
This is for a long time.
It's not for a long time.
It's not for long time.
What?
What is that?
Why?
When in the world did I go back to being a duck?
I know!
What?!
Why didn't I turn back into a girl?!
Shhhh!
The pendant...
A girl!
Shh!
The Pendant!
This is old little duck.
After all, there's nothing more boring than a perfect heroine.
When the spell's broken, duck is just a duck.
Now, show us what the duck will do.
What a mere duck is capable of.
What?
What'll I do?
Without the Pendant, I can't become a girl or Princess Tutu.
Where could it have gone?
My Pendant.
You just try and come for it, Princess Tutu.
Fakir, you're trembling.
Absurd.
Where are you, Princess Tutu?
Quack.
Hey.
Quack!
Oh, no!
I must have fallen!
You were that duck from the other day.
Oh!
The Pendant!
Quack!
I do envy your innocence.
Quack! He's wearing it!
Perhaps Princess Tutu's among these girls.
Mr. Cat, do you smell that? I smell a tasty duck!
Hush, Miss Crocodilia. I'm thinking too hard.
Muto's so handsome. He was always handsome, but now he's even more.
Is it because he's got some of his feelings back?
He's so handsome, isn't he?
Duck will be sad she missed it.
She must be hurting pretty bad from the rejection, huh?
I'd love it if she is.
I hope she's coming back to class soon.
Right, right before she fully recovers.
Well, you know, she does recover quickly.
Miss Piquet, Miss Lillier, if you continue to chit-chat during class, I will have the both of you marry me together.
Well, we're at it! Why not include Miss Duck, who is absent today so all three of you can get married together!
You dance splendidly, Mr. Muto. You're beginning to convey more emotion over street technique.
Yes, sir.
So, you're in love?
Am I?
I can tell, you see.
In love?
Very well.
I will hold a special class on being in love after school for you.
Muto's it.
Yes, sir.
Being in love is a wonderful thing, but there are some things you must be careful about.
In particular, during puberty, self-control is important.
Quack!
The pendant, the pendant!
It's not here!
Don't tell me he took it in there with him!
Quack!
Here it comes!
What do I do?
So, he did have it.
Is he injured?
No, it's a birthmark.
The pendant!
If I could just reach it!
Muto, you really don't know anything.
About regaining your heart.
And what that entails.
What?
Huh?
That damned Krehi.
Is this to say she doesn't see me as a threat?
Muto and Krehi's wedding?
With Vakir for a witness?
Huh?
Oh!
Tonight at midnight.
At the church.
What's Vakir?
The Smith?
Quack!
What's Vakir?
The Smith?
Quack!
What's Vakir?
Which happened?
Tis her third face up after church.
What's Fakir… the smith?
Kha'ron!
Fakir!
Where is the sword?
You haven't been home in ages, yet no greetings for me?
There are plenty of swords in the shop.
No, that sword.
The Lohengrin sword.
I have need of it.
I have to protect Mewtwo from the crows now.
I can't give it to you.
What?
You know that sword is meant for the knight.
You promised that you would let me have it!
That was when you were a child.
Mewtwo has been regaining his heart,
and Princess Tutu has already appeared.
The crows are returning as well.
The legend you told me about as a child is swiftly becoming reality.
If so, this means that I am the knight from the story reborn.
Fakir is a knight?
Reborn?
If I'm the knight, it should be fine if I use the Lohengrin sword.
Fakir, why can't you just leave Mewtwo be?
Leave him be?
You would be much better off forgetting this accursed tale.
It's too late to be saying things like that.
It was on the same day that you took me in after my parents died when you told me, remember?
This mark of yours is the same as in the legend that has been passed down among our people.
I'm sure you'll grow to be strong.
It's a sign that you're the reincarnation of the brave knight who guarded the prince.
In time, it became a source of pride for me.
If it was to protect the people, the prince never feared being injured in the line of duty.
Wow, that's great!
And then, my destiny was suddenly set in motion.
Howacira!
What's that?
Who?
Howacira!
Who, the prince will not be defeated!
Huh?
Howacira!
So, what?!
You're the prince who had lost his head.
Howacira!
Yeah!
MUTOS means a person or character from a legend. Did you know?
No.
You don't know anything, do you, Prince?
Sorry.
Prince is a weird name. How about we call you MUTO? That would be a cool name.
Okay.
Alright! You'll be MUTO starting today!
MUTO had no emotions.
But whenever he saw something weak suffering, no matter the danger, he would rush to try and protect it.
MUTO, it's dangerous!
MUTO!
Fakir…
Stupid. You don't think, do you? You do useless things like that.
Sorry.
Forget helping other people!
Yes.
You just listen to what I tell you. From now on, I'll be protecting you.
I will protect MUTO. That was the promise I made.
Protect MUTO? But then why did you try to shatter his heart?
This fool's errand that you're attempting now is not for MUTO's sake. It's for your own sake, isn't it, Fakir?
What?
The time to fight is drawing closer.
Are you sure you're not afraid of sharing in the same wretched fate as the knight from the story?
I'm not.
You kept calling the prince a good-for-nothing to make sure his heart wouldn't be restored.
Knowing he loved to dance, you enrolled him at the academy to keep him busy. You were too afraid to fight.
No!
There's no way that you'll protect MUTO the way you are now!
Stop it!
You must give it up!
Enough! Any sword will do!
This ends now. Got it?
Yes. I may be afraid of risking my life just as you've accused me, but I want to protect him. The pure-hearted MUTO who's always risked himself.
There's a shard around here somewhere!
Fakir!
I don't know anymore. What's right? What's wrong? The only thing I can tell is Fakir isn't lying. I didn't see it. But this whole time, Fakir's been the same as me. No. He is.
No. He might care about MUTO even more than I do.
I don't know anymore. What's right? What's wrong? The only thing I can tell is Fakir isn't lying. I didn't see it. But this whole time, Fakir's been the same as me. No. He might care about MUTO even more than I do.
Oh, it's you. Sorry you've caught me in a bad moment.
What?
You're crying. What, for my sake?
Take it. You wanted it, didn't you? I will not acknowledge you, Princess Tutu.
Fakir.
Oh, that's right. There's a shard at Karin's house.
Was this really the right thing to do?
There's no way to know that. No matter what you do, you'll only regret it.
You're right.
Just as I thought.
Come. If you don't hurry, the wedding will start without you.
Mr. Karin.
Huh? Princess Tutu? Could it really be?
Please come dance with me, Mr. Karin.
So the tale truly has sprung back to life here in our day. But I still do not know what it is I should do.
I've always regretted telling Fakir the legend. I regret having hurt Fakir. The only things I can do for that child are things that I regret.
No. You should be able to have faith in him.
Have faith in him?
Yes. If Fakir journeys down the path of his heart's conviction, I do not believe he'll regret it, whatever the outcome. Why not have faith in Fakir?
Have faith in Fakir. I am the feeling of regret.
Princess Tutu, thank you. My doubts have cleared.
A book is not a thing to be feared. Turn this page with your own hand.
No way. No way will I succumb to such a miserable fate. I'll change it.
My prince. Princess Tutu.
Princess Tutu.
I've brought you a shard of your heart.
Thank you.
Are you going to Krihi?
Yes. I feel I mustn't run away.
Thank you, Princess Tutu.
For going to the trouble of returning the shards of my husband's heart.
But whether you return them or not makes no difference now, for the prince will become mine tonight.
I will have you bear witness as a nuptial sacrifice.
I've been waiting. Do what you must.
Leave no cause for regret.
Karin.
Go, my son.
What say you, Princess Tutu?
Aren't we just perfect for each other?
I've prepared a special seat for you.
Tutu.
First, we'll have a dance.
I could do away with Tutu this very second, but let's celebrate.
Let's celebrate.
My beautiful prince, you are mine.
Krihi, who are you? Why must you demand I be yours?
Because it is fate.
Fate? Whose fate is that?
It matters not whose fate it is. Fate cannot be changed, not by anyone.
Back, you filthy raven.
Bakir.
So, the coward has arrived.
I will suffer you to be near Mewtwo no more!
Krihi, stop!
What's wrong?
Why are you in such pain?
She has the stone back.
What is it? Hurry and be gone! Or do you have a burning desire to settle things now?
I don't have any wish to fight you.
I have to hurry! Or Valkyra and Mewtwo aren't gonna catch up to me!
If I'm caught wandering out this late, they'll be suspicious.
What the way?
Hey you!
Teehee!
Nothing! What are you doing out this late?
What am I doing?
Well, if I'm out this late, what else could I be doing but that?
That?
You know, that. Well, see ya.
Hey, what's on your... What?
What?
I'm just walking around here.
If I'm caught wandering out this late, they'll be suspicious.
What the way?
Hey, you.
Teehee!
Nothing!
What are you doing out this late?
What am I doing?
Well, if I'm out this late, what else could I be doing but that?
That?
You know, that. Well, see ya.
Hey, what's on your...
What?
Wait!
That pendant.
Goodnight from here!
Princess Tutu?
What do I do?
Could it be he's found out?
Oh dear, it would appear that your identity has slipped out.
What will you do, Princess Tutu?
I'm surprised, to be honest.
Of all the people, I never expected it was you.
Tell me, Doc, do you know about Tutu?
The one Mewtwo wants to see isn't me, it's Princess Tutu, but...
I wish I could have stayed Rue forever, free of Krahi's memories, but now...
The name of this gym here is love.
I am the feeling of love.
The feeling of love, is it?
No, Krahi, stop!
All you children who love stories, come gather round.
...